Guide to the Alfred and Hortense Wagenknecht and Helen and Carl Winter Family Papers TAM.583
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Alfred Wagenknecht and Hortense Allison and Helen and Carl Winter Family Papers
circa 1890-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Winter, Carl, 1906-1991
Crockett, George W.
Wagenknecht, Alfred
Winter, Helen, 1908-2001
TAM.583
12.75 Linear Feet in 7 record cartons, 3 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes
Carl Winter (1906-1991) and Helen Winter (1908-2001) were Communist Party USA activists and officials. Carl Winter was the Chair of the Communist Party of Michigan, was convicted in 1949 under the Smith Act of conspiracy to overthrow the government of the U.S., served three years in prison, and later became the editor of the Party's newspaper, The Worker. His wife Helen was a Smith Act defendant and daughter of Alfred Wagenknecht (1881-1956), a leading member of the Socialist Party, and later a charter member of the Communist Party USA. The collection contains correspondence, including Carl Winter's prison correspondence, family correspondence including that of Alfred Wagenknecht with his wife Hortense and daughters during the 1920s; some documentation of the political activity of Wagenknecht; clippings, most related to Helen Winter's Smith Act trial, and to the Winters' Michigan activism; Detroit Police Department Red Squad files on Carl and Helen Winter; FBI files; speeches; legal documents; Communist Party of Michigan printed ephemera; Allison family materials (the maternal branch of Helen's family); writings; interview transcripts; commemorative and memorial materials and memorabilia, and photographs.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in two series, which have been further arranged in subseries. The series and subseries arrangement of the records is as follows:
Series 1, Alfred Wagenknecht and Hortense Allison Correspondence and Photographs
Subseries 1, Correspondence
Subseries 2, Images and Memorabilia
Series 2, Carl and Helen Winter Papers
Subseries 1, Biographical and Memorabilia
Subseries 2, Correspondence
Subseries 3, Political Activities
Subseries 4, Smith Act Trials and Defense
Subseries 5, Photographs
Historical/Biographical Note
Carl Winter (1906-1991) and Helen Winter (1908-2001) were Communist Party USA activists and officials. Beginning in 1936, Carl Winter held leading posts in the CPUSA in Ohio, Minnesota and California. From 1945 until the mid-1960s, he was Chairman and District Organizer, and Helen Winter was Secretary, of the Communist Party of Michigan. During the McCarthy era, their positions in the CPUSA led to their arrests and indictments, and Carl Winter’s imprisonment for three and a half years, under the Smith Act for conspiracy to overthrow the government of the U.S. After his release from prison in 1955, and the dismissal of charges against Helen Winter in 1958, they resumed leading roles in the Communist Party of Michigan and were both named to the National Committee of the CPUSA. In 1966, they moved to New York City where Carl Winter was editor-in-chief of The Worker, and co-editor of the Daily World. Helen Winter served as the International Affairs Secretary of the CPUSA, and was a founding member of the U.S. Peace Council. Both were members of the CPUSA’s Political Bureau. In 1980, Carl Winter left his editorial post and became Chairperson of the CPUSA’s Central Review Commission. That year the Winters returned to Detroit, where Carl Winter was active in developing the Midwest Labor Institute for Social Studies and Helen Winter operated Global Books.
Carl Winter was arrested on July 20, 1948 and tried and convicted with eleven other national leaders of the CPUSA under the Smith Act in what became known as The United States vs. Dennis. Winter was represented by George Crockett, an African-American attorney, leading member of the National Lawyer's Guild, and future Detroit circuit court judge and United States Congressman from Michigan. Helen Winter was arrested in 1952, and tried and convicted under the Smith Act with five other leading members of the Michigan Communist Party. The trial was appealed to the Supreme Court of the United States, and charges were dismissed in 1957. Throughout her husband’s imprisonment and her own trial, Helen Winter helped organize campaigns on behalf of Smith Act defendants through the National Committee to Win Amnesty for the Smith Act Victims, Families of the Smith Act Victims, and the Civil Rights Congress of Michigan.
Hortense Allison and Alfred Wagenknecht (1881-1956) were leaders of the Socialist Party of America in Washington State in the early twentieth century. In 1913, the family moved to Cleveland, where Wagenknecht was State Secretary of the Ohio Socialist Party. As a result of his active opposition to World War I, he was arrested and imprisoned in 1917 with Charles Ruthenberg in Canton, Ohio. In 1919, Wagenknecht presided over the founding convention, and was named National Secretary, of the Communist Labor Party of America, one of two organizations that would eventually merge to create the CPUSA. In 1924 Wagenknecht managed the fundraising drive for the Daily Worker and helped lead the 1926 strike of textile workers in Passaic, New Jersey.
Scope and Content
The collection contains legal documents, clippings (primarily related to Helen Winter's Smith Act trial), Detroit Police Department Red Squad files on Carl and Helen Winter from the 1940s and 1950s, Communist Party of Michigan and CPUSA printed ephemera and internal documents, writings (published and unpublished), speeches, notebooks, oral histories, photographs, and correspondence, including Carl Winter's prison correspondence with his family and attorneys from the early 1950s. The collection also includes correspondence between Alfred Wagenknecht, his wife Hortense and his daughters, mostly from the 1920s; documentary photographs and negatives from Wagenknecht's trips to London and Germany in 1922, and the Phillipines, China and Japan in 1924; and a scrapbook (circa 1910-1930) of Wagenknecht-Allison family photographs.
Related Archival Materials
Communist Party of the United States of America Records (TAM 132)
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Michele Stone Artt, 2011. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2011.072, 2011.073 and 2011.099. Carl Winter news clippings were found in repository in April of 2014 and added to this collection. The accession number associated with this material is 2014.038.
Women communists |z United States.; Scrapbooks.; Communists -- United States.; Communism |z Michigan.; Communist trials -- United States.; Printed ephemera.; Legal documents.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Winter, Helen, 1908-2001; Winter, Carl, 1906-1991; Wagenknecht, Alfred; Communist Party of the United States of America (Mich.); Communist Party of the United States of America; Abt, John J.; Crockett, George W.; Young, Coleman A.; Hortense, Allison
- I, Alfred Wagenknecht and Hortense Allison Correspondence, Photographs, and Other Material
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence, photographs, postcards and memorabilia created or collected by Alfred Wagenknecht and his wife Hortense Allison Wagenknecht mostly in the 1910s-1930s. Correspondence consists primarily of letters from the 1920s between Alfred and Hortense. Letters provide details of Alfred Wagenknecht’s professional work for the Communist Party USA, the Communist International (Comintern), and the Jimmy Higgins Bookshop in Greenwich Village, managed by Wagenknecht’s brother-in-law, Elmer Allison. Includes letters and related photographs from a trip by Wagenknecht to Germany for a conference in 1922 as a delegate of American Friends of Soviet Russia, and to visit his hometown of Goerlitz. Letters from 1926 provide details of Wagenknecht’s work as one of the CPUSA’s organizers of the Passaic Textile Strike. Many of the travel, documentary and street photographs in this series appear to have been taken by Alfred Wagenknecht himself and include annotations on their backs. These include photographs from a trip to the Philippines, China and Japan in 1924. Several of these photographs were published in the Communist Party’s Workers Monthly, including a photograph of Sun Yat Sen. Photographs from his 1922 trip to Europe include a series documenting a demonstration in Berlin the day after the assassination of Walter Rathenau, and several photographs that include Willi Munzenberg, an organizer of Workers International Relief. This series also includes a photo album documenting the Wagenknecht-Allison family between 1919 and 1925, as well as studio portraits and passport pictures of Wagenknecht and others, postcards from travels to Germany and Asia, and negatives.
  - I, Correspondence
    - Allison, Hortense [General], 1924-1926, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Allison, O.P. [Brother of Hortense Allison]: Letter to Mother, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred with Gene Allison, Gertrude Allison, Helen Allison, Ruth Allison, 1922-1926, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred with Hortense Allison, Jun 18, 1922-Jul 1925, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred with Hortense Allison, Aug 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred with Hortense Allison, Sep 1925-Oct 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred with Hortense Allison, Nov 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred with Hortense Allison, Dec 1925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred with Hortense Allison, Jan 1926-Mar 1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred with Hortense Allison, Apr 1926-Aug 1926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Postcards To [in German], 1949-1951, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - II, Images and Memorabilia
    - East Asia Trip: China [Wuchow, Hong Kong, Canton], May 23, 1924-May 25, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - East Asia Trip: China [Canton], Jun 1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - East Asia Trip: China [Soldaten in Canton, Published in Workers Monthly), circa Jun 1924 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - East Asia Trip: China [Includes Sun Yat Sen and Philippine Delegates to Canton, Published in Workers Monthly], Jun 1924 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - East Asia Trip: China -- Negatives, circa May 1924-Jul 1924 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - East Asia Trip: China and Japan [Shanghai and Yokohama], circa May 21, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - East Asia Trip: China and Japan [Canton, Hong Kong, Shanghai, Kamakura, Kobe, Yokohama, Shimidzu, On Board the Empress], Jun 1924-Jul 1924 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - East Asia Trip: Hawaii [At Haleiwa Hotel and Mormon Temple Grounds, Honolulu], May 5, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - East Asia Trip: Japan [Yokohoma Earthquake, Tokyo Inmates], circa Sep 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - East Asia Trip: Miscellaneous, circa May 1924-Jul 1924 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - East Asia Trip: Philippines, circa Jun 1924 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Europe Trip: Berlin [Demonstration], Jun 25, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Europe Trip: Goerlitz, circa Jun 1922 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Europe Trip: Goerlitz, circa Jun 1922 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Europe Trip: London, Cherbourg, Hamburg, Berlin [Includes Olive Custance, Willi Munzenberg, Young Communist League Members], circa Jun 1922-Jul 1922 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Europe Trip: Potsdam and Goerlitz [Includes Willi Munzenberg and Wife], circa Jun 1922-Jul 1922 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Europe Trip: Ship, Germany, circa Jun 1922 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Europe Trip: Ship, circa 1922 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Europe Trip: Goerlitz -- Negatives, Jun 1922 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Europe Trip: Ship, England, Hamburg, Berlin -- Negatives, circa Jun 1922-Jul 1922 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Europe [?]: Miscellaneous -- Prints and Negatives, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Family Photograph Album [1 of 2], circa 1919-1925 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Family Photograph Album [2 of 2], 1919-1925 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Family Photographs, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Family Photographs -- Negatives, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Memorabilia [Membership Cards, Passport, Certificate of Naturalization], 1889, 1910s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Portraits, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Postcards [Europe, Asia], circa 1920s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 17)
- II, Helen and Carl Winter Papers
  - I, Biographical and Memorabilia
    Series is comprised of biographical materials on and memorabilia belonging to Carl and Helen Winter, and other members of their families, including Helen Winter’s parents Hortense Allison and Alfred Wagenknecht. Includes memorial programs, obituaries, clippings, condolence cards, biographies, oral histories, and honors. Genealogical materials collected by Judith Allison Walters include collections of poetry written by Elmer Allison, and compilations of early family letters.
    - "A Life That Points The Way To The Future," People's Weekly World [Profile of Helen Winter], Sep 3, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "A Message To Alison" [Hortense Allison], Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Allison, Elmer: Obituary, Jul 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Allison, Elmer: Poems and Writings, 1921, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Allison, Hortense: Haymarket-Centered Memoir, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Allison, Hortense: Memorials, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Allison, Hortense: Portrait Of, Nov 1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Allison, Rose Rosen (Sister-in-law of Hortense Allison): Writings [Includes Eulogy for Elmer Allison], 1963-1977, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Allison Machado, Gertrude (Sister of Helen Winter): Obituaries, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Allison Walters, Judith: Genealogical Materials, 1905-2004 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Allison Walters, Judith: "Heartache and Heartbreak: Family Letters 1918-1931", 2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Allison Walters, Judith: "Our Puyallup Houses", Jun 26, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Allison Walters, Judith: "Ozark Memories by Preston Johnson", 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Allison Walters, Judith: "Poems By Elmer Allison", 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Communist Party of Michigan: Welcome Back Celebration for Helen and Carl Winter, Dec 1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Communist Party USA: Gala Reception Honoring Carl and Helen Winter, Dec 1982-Feb 1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - CPUSA: Lifetime Achievement Award for Helen Winter, Mar 1996 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - CPUSA Central Committee: Unique Contribution Award to Helen and Carl Winter, Aug 13, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - CPUSA Political Bureau: Invitation to Farewell to Helen and Carl Winter, Oct 28, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Connecticut District Communist Party: 63rd Anniversary Celebration of the Communist Party USA [Tribute to Helen and Carl Winter], Dec 1982-Jun 1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Daily World: Tribute for John Pittman and Carl Winter, Apr 12, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Detroit City Council: Resolution In Memorium Helen Winter, Jan 25, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Johnson, Preston: "Pities Mr. Oswald" [Letter to the Editor], Nov 1963 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Machado, Eduardo (Brother-in-law of Helen Winter): Memorials, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Manfred, Erica: "I Was a Red Diaper Baby," New York Times Magazine, Nov 2, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Memorabilia [Includes Political Pins, Mementos from Travels], circa 1950-1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - People's Daily World: Certificate for Carl and Helen Winter, Jul 1, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Radio Moscow: Biography of Helen Winter [Russian Transcript and English Translation by Carl Winter], circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Tecla: To Women Mothers of the World [Artwork Inscribed to Helen Winter], 1983 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Memorials, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Weissberg, Lily: Pictured in Clipping from May Day in Cleveland Plain Dealer, May 12, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Winter, Carl: Biography [Fragment], Undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Winter, Carl: Detroit Urban League Distinguished Warrior Plaque, Feb 14, 1985 (Oversize 11)
    - Winter, Carl: Memorials [1 of 4], Nov 1991-Apr 1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Winter, Carl: Memorials [2 of 4], Nov 1991-Mar 1992 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Winter, Carl: Memorial [Includes Letter from Reverend Charles A. Hill] [3 of 4], circa 1924-1991 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Winter, Carl: Memorial [Audio Tape of Remarks by George Crockett] [4 of 4], Apr 5, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Winter, Carl: Oral Histories, 1988, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Winter, Carl and Claude Lightfoot: Internment Ceremony at Waldheim Ceremony, May 1992 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Winter, Carl and Helen Winter: High School Diplomas, Jun 20, 1924, Jun 19, 1925 (Oversize 11)
    - Winter, Helen: 85th Birthday Tribute in Detroit, Michigan [1 of 2], Dec 1992-Feb 1993 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Winter, Helen: 85th Birthday Tribute in Detroit, Michigan [2 of 2], Dec 1992-Feb 1993 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Winter, Helen: "A Glimpse Of The Past -- Working For The Future" (Draft of Article for People's Weekly World), Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Winter, Helen: Memorials, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Winter, Helen: Oral History [1 of 2], 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Winter, Helen: Oral History [2 of 2], Nov 1992-May 1993 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Winter, Michele: Commencement Program From Marygrove College, May 16, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - II, Correspondence
    Scope and Content Note
    Series is comprised primarily of Carl and Helen Winter’s correspondence during the period of their Smith Act trials from 1949 through the late-1950s, and Carl Winter’s prison correspondence between 1951-1955. The series also includes Carl and Helen Winter’s personal and professional correspondence from the 1960s-1990s.
    Carl Winter’s prison correspondence with wife Helen, daughter Michele, father Simon Weissberg, mother-in-law Hortense Allison, and attorneys George Crockett and John Abt, comprises a significant portion of the correspondence. The series also includes Helen Winter’s correspondence with prison authorities on behalf of her husband, with her attorneys Ernest Goodman and John Abt, fellow Smith Act defendants, wives of CPUSA leaders, and the advocacy groups National Committee to Win Amnesty for the Smith Act Victims and Families of the Smith Act Victims. Other correspondents include Benjamin Davis, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Gus Hall, Meridel Le Sueur, and Henry Winston. Formats include letters, telegrams, cards, and drawings by Michele Winter.
    - Allison, Gertude [Sister of Helen Winter]: Correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence, 1943-1953 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence, 1959-1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Allison Walters, Judith: Letter to Winter, Helen, Jan 3, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Aptheker, Herbert: Letter to Winter, Helen, Mar 16, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Ariyoshi, Koji [Hawaii Smith Act Defendant]: Letter to Winter, Helen, Mar 10, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Bachrach, Marian: Letter to Winter, Helen, 1952, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Cassidy, David: Letter to Judge Harold Medina, Sep 16, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Christoffel, Ann: Letter to Patterson, William [Civil Rights Congress], Jun 26, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Columbus County Committee Communist Party, Ohio: Letter to the Winter Family, Dec 21, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Crane, Henry [Central Methodist Church]: Letter to Winter, Carl, Dec 17, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Abt, John, 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Bachrach, Marion, Jan 28, 1953, May 15, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Davis, Benjamin, Jul 30, 1951, Sep 5, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Crockett, George: Letter to Dennis, Eugene, Jul 30, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Gannet, Betty, Jan 19, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Green, Abner [American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born], Jan 1953-Feb 1953 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Crockett, George: Letter to Perry, Pettis, Jan 12, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Prison Authorities, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Rabinowitz, Victor, Dec 1954-Feb 1955 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Stachel, Jack, Jul 1951-Sep 1951 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with United States Board of Parole, Jan 1953-Mar 1953 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Williamson, Mae, Jan 28, 1953, Feb 19, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Crockett, George: Letter to Winter, Carl and Helen Winter, Feb 4, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Dave White Section [Detroit]: Letter to Gurley-Flynn, Elizabeth, Oct 1, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Davis, Benjamin: Letter to Winter, Carl, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Flynn, Katherine [Relative of Elizabeth Gurley Flynn]: Holiday Drawing for Carl Winter, Dec 1953 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Ganley, Ann: Letter to Winter, Carl, Oct 3, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Ganley, Patty: Letter to Winter, Carl, Oct 1949 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Gurley Flynn, Elizabeth: Correspondence with Winter, Carl, circa 1949, Dec 1953 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Hall, Arvo: Postcard to Winter, Michele, Undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Hall, Elizabeth: Letters to Winter, Helen, Dec 27, 1952, Sep 2, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Hall, Gus and Henry Winston: Letter to Allison, Hortense [Re: Lenin Centennial Memorial Medal], Mar 4, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Ishdorzh, S. [Mongolian People's Party]: Letter to Winter, Carl, Mar 4, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Le Sueur, Meridel: Letter to Dennis, Peggy, Jul 13, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Le Sueur, Meridel: Letter to Winter, Carl, Sep 1949 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Licht, Mary: Letter to Winter, Helen, Oct 28, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - McKie, Bill: Correspondence with Winter, Carl, 1949, 1953, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - McKie, Bill: Letter to Winter, Helen, Dec 8, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Pomeroy, Bill: Letter to Winter, Helen [Re: Phillipines Communist Party], Feb 10, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Rubin, Daniel: Letter to Becchetti, Arnold, Undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Rust, Fritz: Letter to Winter, Carl, Mar 10, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - US Department of Justice, Bureau of Prisons: Letter to Allison, Hortense, Oct 7, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Winter, Carl and Helen Winter, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Weissberg, Simon: Letter to Allison, Hortense, Sep 21, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Weissberg, Simon: Correspondence with Prison Authorities, 1951, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Williamson, John: Correspondence with Isserman, Abraham [Attorney], Mar 1952 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Winter, Carl: Cards [1 of 2], 1949-1954, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Winter, Carl: Cards [2 of 2], 1953 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Winter, Carl: Postcards and Letters, Sept 13, 1949-Sep 28, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Winter, Carl: Telegrams, Sep 13, 1949-Oct 19, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence [John Williamson, Carl Stellato, Daniel Rubin, James Jackson and Louis Weinstock, Carl Haessler], 1956-1966 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence [Young Workers Liberation League, Betty Smith, Harry Mensh, Lou Diskin and Phil Bart, Danny Rubin, Arnold Becchetti, Scott Marshall], 1980-1985 (Box 4, Folder 55)